Inside this box is a really interesting little gadget I want to show you today.
今天我给大家介绍的是这个盒子里的小玩意
This is a magnetic tape viewer.
这是个磁带磁性查看器
With this, you can actually see the audio that's recorded on a tape.
利用这个，你可以清晰地看到记录在磁带上的音频信号
I'll demonstrate how it works with this quarter-inch tape.
我一会用这个四分之一英寸的磁带来演示
First, I'll layer recorded section of the tape out flat,
首先，我要将一段录过音的磁带片段抽出来，并铺平
and then place the viewer down on top of it.
然后将查看器放在这个上面
Making sure I put it on the recorded side of the tape.
保证其放在录过音的那一面
And within a couple of seconds, the pattern of the audio
几秒后，磁带上音频信号的
that's on the tape appears in the window.
样子就显示在窗口中了
Now as you could imagine this is not the easiest thing to shoot,
当然，正如你能所想，拍下来这个可不是什么容易事
so I've had to break out the macro lens for this video.
所以我祭出了微距镜头来拍这个
But let's take one more look at that.
现在咱来看看这个
So popping it down on the tape, I can determine that
将其放在磁带上时，我能分辨出
this is a four track recording.
这个磁带上有四个磁轨
I can also see that, it's more than likely to separate stereo programs
而且我还注意到，这个好像是将两个
one going in each direction, as track one matches up with track three,
双声道给分开了，比如一磁轨和三磁轨是一对
and track two goes with track four.
二磁轨和四磁轨是一对
Now you might be wondering how much audio in time.
现在你可能在想：这段磁带能放出多长的音频
We're looking at here, how long would it take to play that section of table.
我们来看看，这段摆在桌子上的磁带能放多长时间的音频
You probably aren't wondering that but I'm going to tell you anyway.
你也许没考虑到，但是我现在还是要说
So this tape is on a seven inch reel, which is a four track.
那么，这个磁带是放在七英寸的卷盘上，也就是四轨
So most commonly, recorded at a speed of seven and a half
一般来说，这个是以7.5英寸每秒
or three point seven five inches per second.
或者是3.75英寸每秒的速度录制的
Or in the case of my reel-to-reel that's listed in metric
要是听不懂的话，我开盘机上显示的是
as 19 or 9.5 cm a second.
19厘米每秒，或者是9.5厘米每秒
And playing the tape reveals that it's been recorded at that slower speed.
我在播放磁带后，意识到这盘磁带是以较慢的速度录制的
So it's a 9.5 cm per second recording.
那么，这个就是以9.5厘米每秒的速度录制的了
And the window on the tape viewer is three centimeters across,
再来看查看器窗口，这个是三厘米
which means that that's approximately a third of a second.
那么，这段磁带就能播放三分之一秒的音乐了
That's visible in the window.
而这段音乐呢，你就能在查看器窗口里看见了
Now moving on to how it works...
现在咱来看看这个的原理......
Well, it's quite likely a familiar with a toy like this.
额，这个东西的原理和这个玩具的原理差不多
The idea being that you use a magnet to manipulate the iron filings
也就是当你用磁铁来移动铁屑的方向时
that are contained inside the clear plastic window.
铁屑就在这个透明的塑料盒子中移动
Well, imagine if those iron filings were much much finer
而如果这些铁屑更细
and also suspended in a liquid, and then
并且悬浮在液体中呢
rather than requiring a magnet on a stick to move them.
这时，你不必使用磁铁或磁棒来移动它们了
That'd be fine enough to be attracted by the much weaker magnetic signal
它们足够的细，所以它们可以侦测到更微弱的磁信号
that's recorded on a tape.
比如磁带上的磁信号
The magnetic attraction of a tape, while weak, is still strong enough to
磁带上的磁信号，虽然很弱，但是也足以
pass through the thin metal base of the viewer,
能穿过查看器底部的金属片了
and manipulate the ultrafine suspended ferric oxide particles
然后让其上的十分细的悬浮氧化铁粒子移动
to reveal the recorded pattern.
来显示出磁带上的磁信号
Now the earliest mention of seen of this device
目前关于这个东西的最早记载
is in this issue of broadcast engineering from February 1964.
是在1964年2月的出版的《Broadcast Engineering》杂志
注：参考译名《广播工程》
It appears on the new products page for that month.
它是出现在“本月新上市产品”栏目中的
A number of potential uses are listed, including amongst others.
还列出了很多潜在用途，包括其他方面
Checking for head alignment, track placement and dropouts.
例如检查磁头是否校准，查看磁轨位置和边缘
注：这些开盘带之类的术语我全都不知道是什么意思，有谁懂的话，发下弹幕补充一下呗:-)
It also says, it can be used to determine if tools tape heads or tape guides are magnetized.
这上面还说，这个东西还能侦测到磁头，磁带导引器这些东西是否被磁化
The price in 1964 was listed as $50.
这个玩意1964年时卖50美元
With inflation, that's a little over $400 nowadays.
算上通货膨胀的话，现在卖400多美元
Looking at the patent number that's shown on the viewer,
再来看看查看器上面印的专利号
reveals that this was granted in 1961, but it was applied for in 1958.
显示是在1961年授予的，问题是，他们早在1958年就申请了
Originally though, the use case was a little bit less certain in the document.
原先的申请档案中，这个发明的目的没写清楚
It states that magnetic recorded tape is often criticzed,
这上面说：录音磁带广受差评
because the signals are invisible.
因为录上去的信号看不见
It states this as hampered sales due to a reluctance
这上面还说：这个特性导致磁带销售缓慢，因为
from some organizations to move away from punch
因为有些机构不愿将打孔带替下来
tape and cards, where the data was visible to the eye.
因为打孔带上可以看见数据:-|
And therefore, could be verified by a person.
从而，这个人就可以辨别信息了
The proposed apparatus showed in the documentation
而且，这个文档中正在设计的东西
is also significantly different in design to the finished product.
和我手中的最终成品还是有所差异的
Now initially, I wondered if 3M had purchased this patent
原先呢，我想3M是不是买进这个专利
and adapted that original idea for their viewer.
并采纳了这个查看器的设计思路
But you can see, on the patents, it was three Ms from the beginning.
但是如你所见，在专利文件开头有三个M
Or as it's written in full here: the Minnesota Mining and Manufacturing Company.
还有这个全称：明尼苏达矿业及机器制造公司
And the primary name that's listed on the application:
还有这份申请中的第一个申请人：
Robert J. Youngquist, was a career 3M employee.
Robert J. Youngquist，当时是3M的员工
He was later inducted into their Carleton Society, which is
它后来被引进3M的Carleton Society
kinda 3M's Hall of Fame, and that was in 1991.
这个相当于3M的名人堂，他是在1991年被引入的
The magnetic tape viewer that here in these colleagues devised 33 years earlier.
而他们是在33年前设计的磁带磁性查看器
They must have remained on the market for a number of years,
这些东西大概在市场上售卖了几年
as it's mentioned again, in this magazine article from 1973.
正如1973年发行的杂志上的文章所言
By this point though, they're suggesting that you could use it
说到这个，他们建议你用这个来
to check the head alignment of an 8-track tape.
检测八轨磁带头是否对齐
So let's have a look at one of those!
好吧，咱来试试这个
Now this one was quite a bit more difficult to get a good picture
额，要把这个拍下来还是有一定难度的
of what issue is that, the tracks are really fine.
问题在于，磁轨太细了
And we're also trying to capture an 0.3 second window,
我们仍然尝试拍下有0.3秒音频磁带的磁性分布
and all of those eight tracks are playing something loud enough to show up clearly.
而这段磁带的八个轨道，信号都很强，能够让我们很清晰地看见它们
But you can just about make out here, all of the eight tracks on this tape.
你现在就能辨别出这个磁带上的八个轨道
The eight track I'm using is a stereo tape,
这盘八轨带是双声道的
so that means it consists of full stereo program.
也就是整盘带都是双声道信号
So those are made up of pairs of tracks.
也就是说，这些轨道都是成对的
And they're laid out on the tape as tracks 1 & 5,
它们在磁带上是以1和5
2 & 6, 3 & 7, and finally, 4 & 8.
2和6，3和7，以及4和8的方式配对的
It's perhaps a little bit easier to see it on this next shot.
也许在下一张图片中，我们可以看得更清楚
Where the fourth program is currently silent.
目前磁带上的第四轨道是没有音频信号的
So that means, we can see for example that tracks 2 & 6 are definitely a matching pair.
也就是说，我们可以分明地看见这些轨道的配对关系，比如2轨和6轨
Okay, let's look at something else. An old store loyalty points card.
好的，咱现在来看点别的。一张十分老的商店会员积分卡
Popping the viewer on here, and you can clearly see the
咱现在把查看器放在上面，然后你就能看到
magnetic signal that's recorded on the strip.
记在磁条上面的磁信号
And next, let's move on to a compact cassette.
现在，我们再来看看稀松平常的盒式磁带
Now, this one showed up particularly well.
这个磁带在显示器中显示得很清楚
You can clearly see the two stereo programs, one for each side.
你可以分明地看到两个双声道信号，一边一个
And this also shows how much of a gap is left, only middle of a compact cassette tape.
你也可以看到这两个轨道间的空隙有多窄，就是磁带中间的一小段
And there is a real stereo I use the viewer for.
这里我们还要用查看器来看看这个
A while ago, I bought this actors master tape.
很久之前，我买了这盘播音员试音带
It's from a talent agency, it was used to showcase actors voices for
这原先是经纪公司做的，用来展现播音员的声色
potential advertisement jobs.
用来看他们适不适合给广告配音
Well, from playing it back at my four track machine,
我把这盘带放在开盘机上播放后
I could determine the speed of the tape, and also,
我可以确定磁带录制的速度，而且
I know that it's not a four-track as the recording only plays one way.
我还知道这不是四轨磁带，而且只能朝一个方向播放
But I wasn't sure if any of it was in stereo.
但是我不知道这盘磁带是不是双声道的
Well, to find that out, I can put the view on and putting it down on the tape,
好吧，为了看出这个，我把查看器放在磁带的上面
shows that it's actually a mono recording,
看出这个就是单声道的
just one track all the way across the width of the tape.
整条磁带只有这一条单声道音轨
And so, break things up for a bit.
那么，咱截下来一段来听听
Here's a brief sample of a clip from that reel.
以下是这盘磁带的片段
Let's have a look a couple more things through the viewer.
咱们现在用这个查看器再来看点别的吧
This is a two-track stereo tape recorded at 19 centimeters a second.
这个是双轨的磁带，录制速度为19厘米每秒
So just like that advert reel.
所以这个和刚才的广告试音带没什么区别
What you're looking at here is approximately one-sixth of a second of audio.
你现在所看到的是大约六分之一的声音信号
Now the viewer doesn't work with everything though.
但这个查看器不能看到所有的磁信号:-(
This is what a DCC looks like, which is nothing visible.
这个是DCC在查看器中看到的效果，啥都看不见
注: DCC=Digital Compact Cassette 数字式高密录音带
It's definitely a recorded section of audio, too.
可这段绝对是录上音的
It's no surprise it doesn't show up though
额，它显示不出来是正常的
because a DCC has 18 incredibly thin digital tracks across its width.
因为DCC磁带上有18个十分细的数码轨道
It's just going to be too fine for it to register.
这些轨道十分的细，难以被侦测到
And next is what the recorded section looks like on a VHS tape,
下一个实验对象是VHS磁带
but the only thing that's visible this time
但是你只能看到边缘的
is the controlled track that's a long wad edge.
控制信号轨道
And finally one the church that I wanted to show is that
好的，最后一个我想展示的是
when the viewer is placed back in its case, it displays the 3M logo.
当你把查看器放回盒子中时，你会看到3M的标志
Therefore, if you ever do see one of these in a shop,
也就是说，当你在商场看到他的话
you can test whether it's working without having a magnetic tape with you.
你不必带一段磁带来检测这个东西能不能用
A word of warning though, the faroe oxide in the fluid
还有个问题需要注意，这个东西放久的话
can settle to one side over time.
流体中的氧化铁会聚集到一侧
This initially was the case with mine after a couple of minutes,
一开始我以为是我没用好，过了几分钟
So gently massaging the screen in a circular motion.
我轻轻地打转查看器才解决了这个问题
The solution dispersed evenly again.
这个问题时常还会出现:-(
That said you'd be very lucky to find one of these for sale.
还有一件事，你要能找到的话，你就太幸运了
I had a save search on eBay activated for one of these
在我买到这个东西前
FOR FOUR YEARS before one turned up for sale.
我已经花了四年时间在eBay上寻找这个
However, while researching for this video,
但是呢，我在查资料时
I found that there's a company making a modern-day equivalent
我看到有家公司在做这个设备
So if you are interested, I'll put a link to them in
所以，如果你感兴趣的话，我会将这个公司的连接
the video description text box.
放在简介区里
And I hope you've enjoyed having a look at
希望大家对今天我展示的小东西感兴趣
this fascinating little device here today.
并且看得愉快
But that is it for the moment.
不过，本期节目到此就要结束了
As always, thanks for watching.
一如既往，感谢大家观看:-)
十分感谢这些在
Pateron上赞助我的人
以下是Techmoan在介绍区的Q&A节选
问：我能用这个看到软盘上的磁信号吗？
A) 不行:-( 我试验了5.25吋的软盘，两面都没有:-(
Q) CAN IT SEE WHATS ON A FLOPPY DISK?
A) No - It didn’t show anything on a 5.25” floppy I tested (BOTH SIDES)
Q) 你可以买些磁性观察纸来做这些事啊
A) 它们的敏感度不一样......至少我买到的不行。它们不能显示磁带上的信号。
我试了好几遍都没有:-(
Q) You can buy these sheets of magnetic viewing paper that do the same thing.
A) They don’t have the same resolution or sensitivity - at least the ones I’ve bought don’t. They can’t show the magnetic signal and track layout on a tape. Nothing registered when I tried.
Q) You can use this fluid stuff that does the same job
A) A few people are mentioning various ways to do this with a liquid smeared on the tape. These were known about, and likely made, by 3M as well. But one reason for the development of the magnetic tape viewer was that it was a ‘non destructive’ way to read the tape. Here’s an except from their patent application where they mention one of the existing and alternative methods to do the same thing.
Q) 你可以自己做这种流体来看嘛
A) 有人确实提过很多方法来将液体涂抹到磁带上来看磁性分布，3M知道这个方法
而且3M可能也试过这个东西，但是开发磁带查看器的原因之一是，它可以无伤读取磁带磁性分布。
他们在专利申请中提到过，而且也提出了很多方法来做这件事
Q) Who is the voice in the Datsun Commercial?
A) Danny Dark
Q) 那个广告是谁配的音？
Q) 盒子左边的白色平台是干啥的?
A) 那是个观察板，想要仔细看的话，请空降2:51
Q) What’s the white pad on the left for.
A) Thats the ‘Viewing Pad’ - to see a picture of it being used - freeze the video at 02:51
本视频由SuperBart翻译，原作者Techmoan发布于2020-2-19